Acceleration Mode... on!
What the hell was that, dude?!
Shit!
Oh crap!
Then all you have to do... is let
it fall right into the basket.
Hoo boy, they've really
got us on the ropes now!
Don't make it sound like we've already lost!
We're just getting started! Isn't that right?
We're in a tight spot,
I'm not sure what to do.
I guess maybe we should
put Taro on the bench.
I can hear you from over here, damn geezer!
Just shut up and watch.
Forget that shorty, I'm gonna
fly past their whole team!
Oh crap, now he's even more wound up.
He's gonna go on a rampage
soon, there's no doubt.
And I keep telling you,
that's exactly what we want.
Huh?
We're going to have Taro...
trample all over that kid's tiny wings.
Ahiru no Sora
Kitasumi!
Let's score!
Here they come!
Versus
Kitasumi!
Let's score!
Yasuhara, watch out for any passes!
Kitasumi!
Let's score!
Defensive foul, #4!
Two free-throws!
Dammit. She called a foul on me?
Hey, Yasuhara. Don't drop
your hands like that.
Blocking passes from above
is an absolute must.
Okay.
Awesome! He nailed both of those free-throws!
Keep it up, Konishi!
T-T-T-Taro?!
No way, is he also doing...?
Full court man-to-man?!
Whenever someone puts me through shit,
I never sit and take it.
Starting now, I'll give you
a taste of your own medicine!
Here we go again...
He always tries to get even.
Ouch...
Why the heck did you hit me?!
Because you hit me first!
I said I was sorry!
Suffer the pain that I did!
He's the most hardheaded idiot, I swear.
Always dishing it out, but
can never take it himself.
Okay. Let's play cat and mouse then.
I'm not gonna let him get the better of me!
Dumbass! Don't let him provoke you!
You won't even last half the game like that!
Chill out, just leave him be.
This actually works in our favor.
Just so you know, my heart
runs on pure horsepower!
"Pure horsepower"...?
Nobody outruns me!
Sora?
Are you still sulking about it?
This isn't new, you've
always been a bench player.
I'm sick of it, this is discrimination!
It's like saying short kids
aren't allowed to play!
Don't be ridiculous.
I'm dead serious! That coach has never once
put me in an actual game!
How did you compare to everyone
in the last training session?
They already announced the results, right?
You're looking at the number one overall!
Even in the dribble marathon?
And the 50-meter dash?
Of course!
But nothing changed, I'm
still treated the same.
It makes me hate everything.
And what about the endurance marathon?
Well, I was...
...only 4th. No, actually 5th.
But what does that have to
do with basketball anyway?
It doesn't matter how fast
you can run if you can't
keep it up for an extended
period of time, right?
Basketball games last for 40 minutes.
Dashing around the court
for that whole time is incredibly taxing.
Having stamina and speed is
vital for any short player.
But becoming the most capable
runner on a team is only
half of what they need to
be considered good, I'd say.
Then... what's the other half?
That's simple.
Becoming the most capable runner
who plays out on the court, silly.
Taro is actually having
trouble keeping up with him!
Even though that shrimp
has already been running for 10 minutes!
It'll take way more than
that to stop our boy.
And since the other team
is doing man-to-man...
...we can easily spread their defense apart.
But more than anything,
I wanna make that seaweed haired punk cry!
They're charging in!
Help!
I don't need any help!
I'll shut him down myself!
Damn you!
Rebound!
From out here?!
Why?! How did that shot go in?!
A 5-point lead!
Kitasumiyoshi
Kuzuryu
We're leaving them in the dust!
Come on, Taro! Just let Konishi
handle all of the rebounds!
SHUT YOUR FACE!
But wow, it must be exhausting for that guy
to switch to full-court defense now.
Sheesh! He's just wasting energy
with all those pointless moves.
Oh, wait! Is that why you
gave Taro a hard time, Coach?
You got him all wound
up on purpose and now...
Not yet.
He's not done, we've only
just gotten started.
The other team is using zone defense!
Let's try and hit 'em before they set it up!
He's too clingy! Damn squirt!
I've had just about enough of this bullshit!
Taro?!
Huh?!
He went to the back court?!
How should I react to that?
Should I prioritize the ball?
No, my job is man-to-man,
and that means I have to stick with him!
Dumbass!
Don't waste energy chasing after him!
They won't bother passing to him either way!
Holy shit! That was a
sick move he just pulled!
Yeah it was cool, but also looked like
a total waste of effort.
You can't touch this! I dare you to even try!
Konishi, head for the middle!
He's going for it, Yasu!
Don't let him through!
Pass it here!
Man, his legs just won't stop!
I can't believe how athletic Kabachi is!
But no matter what, I can't
let him score any more points!
In the paint!
Dammit!
He's totally blocked!
He moved!
He took a step!
Travelling!
Shoot, that was so close!
We managed to get it all the way in the paint!
This is nuts. It's almost like
Taro is superhuman with all his moves!
I sure as hell wouldn't last a
quarter trying to defend him.
Kurumatani...
Kuzu High ball! Throw-in!
Oh, these feel really nice.
They were worth the high price.
I better put them to good use!
Is somebody else here?
Hey, Chiba.
Yo.
What are you doing here?
We have today off, you know.
Don't give me that.
Nobody would agree to go
to the movies with me.
And I hate going by myself.
And what about you? I thought you were
going to a studio or something.
I ran into some surprises on my way there.
Surprises?
All of a sudden...
...I really started craving
to play basketball.
Huh?
The inter-high preliminaries...
...I think we're in for a ride
right from the get-go this year.
Something's got him unusually pumped up.
Hey, Tokiwa?
Mind if I ask you a question?
What is it?
Do you think joining a band
would net me a girlfriend?
Quit joking around with me.
Okay, then...
Foul, #5 on defense!
What the hell? I didn't hit him!
I just gave him a bit of a shove!
Pushing is a foul, dude.
Yasuhara, that's your
third foul in this game.
You gotta be more careful.
Goddammit, stupid Yabuuchi.
She just keeps blowing that
annoying whistle on me.
Hold up, maybe it's cuz
she's got the hots for me.
As if!
Kuzuryu
Kitasumiyoshi
They're already halfway through
the third quarter of the game...
...but they've managed to fend off
a Kitasumi comeback this whole time.
That's solid proof of how
effective Sora is on defense.
He really does run like nobody else.
That shot is off!
It's going to come down near you, Momoharu!
Rebound!
I know already!
That bastard... he just
straight up smacked my hand!
Here they come again!
Watch the inside!
Crap!
Good job! I can hear the
basket calling my name!
Badass!
Nice, Kite!
Out of bounds! Kitasumi ball!
He totally abandoned his zone just now.
What the heck was that guy thinking?
That's what I want to know...
This cocky punk.
I'm getting sick of standing
in the same damn place the whole game!
Zone really just isn't my thing.
When that pass came at me,
I know for sure that guy was in the paint.
Does that guy just move at
the speed of light or what?
And even worse...
...he's got the edge on
me in the cool department!
Thanks a bunch, Kite!
Sorry you had to take a risk to cover for me.
But if you hadn't done anything,
then Kabachi would have definitely scored on us.
Whatever, I didn't do it to help you out.
I did it because I figured
it would work, that's all.
Anyway...
...don't get caught by any
more of their lame screens.
What happened? Are you already tapped out?
Nope. I could keep running
for another 100 years!
They're focused in the middle!
Throw them off with some passes!
Konishi, keep your eyes on the shot clock!
Kitasumi!
Let's score!
Let's score! Uh...
Defense!
Kitasumi!
Let's score!
Kato! Over here! Gimmie the
ball! Ball! Kato! Ball!
Kitasumi!
Let's score!
Get rid of your defender first!
I can't let fatigue get the better of me.
I have to hold him back no matter what!
I've practiced how to play
defense ever since I was little!
I've learned everything and anything
that doesn't require height!
So that I could become the one
who runs on the court the most!
Hasebe, don't risk it! Pass it back!
A steal!
What?!
H-he's quick!
That shrimp is gonna take
it all the way by himself!
Go!
We're gonna be celebrating tonight!
Shit!
Forget about it. Just stay focused.
Never thought he'd last this long.
I gotta admit, even I'm a little surprised.
But it's fine...
...the gap is about to start
getting wider and wider.
Katori! We're counting on
you for some solid passing!
Find a way through them!
Huh?
Am I crazy or did Kabachi just
get faster all of a sudden?
Impossible. Does that mean he's been
holding back this whole time?
No, he doesn't look capable
of something that shrewd.
It must be my imagination.
I'm wrong! He's definitely getting faster!
We've been at this for more
than 20 minutes straight now... so how?!
All right, Kato! Gimme that ball!
Is it actually me... who's getting slower?!
Help!
Kato! Pass it inside!
That stupid shrimp!
Did he forget why he's doing man-to-man?!
Dammit!
How can this guy be so quick on the shot?!
He did it!
That was awesome, Senpai!
You stupid shrimp! Don't just
let him run free like that!
Sorry! The sun totally got in my eyes and...
Player substitution!
I'm out?
Kuzuryu
Kitasumiyoshi
Uh, wait, no! Hold on!
You don't need to sub me out!
I'm not even feeling tired, I swear!
I can whistle a tune
totally fine, just watch!
Sorry! Please call off the substitution!
Listen, Kurumatani.
You're subbing out for Chucky.
This is... a direct order from your coach.
The tide is turning!
Let's score one after the other until we win!
Defense! Defense! Defense!
Well, well. Hmph.
He really held in there.
Chucky, you're looking really stiff.
We're gonna pass the ball
around, so just take it easy.
R-right!
Pass the ball, I got it!
P-pass, pass, pass, pass, pass,
pass... pass... pa... ss...
Don't hold on to it for too long.
Okay!
Loose ball!
It's a turnover!
S-sorry guys!
No prob, shake it off!
Damn. We can't make a fast break.
Offense! Offense! Offense!
Listen up, everybody!
Just stick to our zone defense!
And Chucky, you go man-to-man
with #7 starting from half-court!
Be sure to deny him any passes, Chucky!
We can't let them move
the ball into the paint!
Roger! I'm all over it!
They got the ball through to him in no time!
What's the deal with their #6?
Shit, I finally get free of
the little boy and now this.
I ran myself ragged practicing how to do defense!
I won't let him past me!
T-too fast!
Nice move, Taro!
Their defense is full of holes!
Slippery bastard!
He totally left me in the dust...
And our shorty was keeping up
with that guy this whole time?!
This is nuts. He's on a
totally different level!
I wanna swap with somebody else!
Kitasumi! Fight! Kitasumi! Fight!
Please provide each other with cover
if they break through to the center!
Be very careful when they're in low post!
Get on #7! Our defense
in the paint is lacking!
Defense! Defense! Defense!
Goddammit...
Goddammit!
I can keep going! I know I can still run!
Dammit!
Hang in there, this is
the time to be tenacious.
It's too early to get upset, don't you think?
We're still a long way from losing this game.
The game...
Anyway, is your knee feeling okay?
My knee?
You stumbled earlier,
and I thought maybe you'd been injured...
Why's that? I'm totally fine!
Really?
I've been running like that my whole life,
and never even broken a bone!
Look!
I'm so glad!
For right now, you should
focus on resting up.
Damn you! Hiyah!
Defensive foul! #5!
Hey! Isn't their #5 already
on his fourth foul?
Sweet! It's still only the third quarter!
Timeout by Kuzuryu High!
Yasuhara, I told you to be
more careful with the fouls!
Sorry.
Do you WANT to get ejected
from the game again?
Out of our three noobs,
Yasu is the only one who can dribble decently.
Losing him now would hurt quite a bit.
Hey, Nanao.
Don't you think we should
switch up our defense?
With Tinytown on the bench,
there's no point in keeping up a zone D.
Except we haven't been using zone D
solely for the benefit of Tinytown.
If we do man-to-man there's
a strong possibility
that Yasu and Chucky will
get overwhelmed in a 1-on-1.
One reason we chose zone D is to fortify
our ability to help and recover when necessary.
Isn't that right, Nao?
Exactly!
For the time being, we'll have
Yasuhara sub out for Nabe.
Sure.
As for our defense, we'll
switch to the 2-3 zone,
which is the very first
formation we practiced.
You remember how to do that, right Nabe?
Uh, yeah, I think so!
Wait just a sec, Nao!
Could I... sub out for somebody, too?
Huh? What do you mean?
I mean, Tinytown is ready to go right?
I'm like... already...
Man, the look in his eyes is so intense...
And that's how he looks
after running for nearly 30 minutes straight?
Meanwhile, I've only run
for like 2 or 3 tops.
Shit!
What is it, Chucky?
Nothing, forget what I just said!
Huh?
We don't have to change our
zone formation, either!
All I gotta do is put a
stop to their #7, right?
Until Tinytown is back in the game,
I'll shut down #7 even if it means
I have to slug him in the face!
He totally nailed both of those free-throws!
That ties up the score!
The other team is missing the guy
who was carrying them!
Let's use this chance to take them by storm!
Defense! Defense! Defense!
Idiots.
Get your heads out of your asses.
That shorty doesn't carry our team.
A three?!
I'm the top scorer here.
Just try and stop me if you can!
Jeez, what's his problem?!
He's really pissing me off!
Go kick the bucket somewhere.
Smug jerk.
The momentum is still
on our side, don't stop!
Let's make sure we score the next one!
I'm ready to sink a three-pointer!
Gimme the ball!
Kitasumi!
Let's score!
Come on, guys! Just keep
passing the ball to Taro!
Kitasumi!
Let's score!
Full-court?!
Can their #6 really run enough to cover him?!
Again? Give me a break.
Chucky! Don't push yourself!
Playing full-court D is really,
REALLY exhausting, you know!
But Tinytown kept it up
for a full 30 minutes.
Lasting a measly 10 minutes
should be a piece of cake!
Chucky, you brave fool! Men
like you are one of a kind!
Guys... I'm counting on
you to handle things here!
Huh?
He shook him off again!
Oh no, Chucky!
Your defense is too weak.
Huh?
WHAAAAAAT?!
Ahiru no Sora
Next Time: Now...
Next time: "Now..."